good morning welcome to modules in one
早上好，欢迎将模块合二为一
lesson so this is a pretty quick
课程，这是一个非常快的过程
overview but a fair bit deeper than I
概述，但比我还深入
was able to go in the keynote yesterday
昨天能够参加主题演讲
I'm gonna do but mostly live coding in
我会做的，但主要是在
fact entirely live coding show you some
实际上完全是实时编码，向您展示了一些
basics about the module system are going
有关模块系统的基础知识正在发展
to take a very simple you know the the
简单地说，您知道
most trivial hello world application and
最琐碎的Hello World应用程序和
convert it into modules and see how the
将其转换成模块，看看如何
module system works how to how to build
模块系统工作原理
things with the module system how to
东西与模块系统如何
build modular jar files see how the
构建模块化的jar文件，了解如何
module system enforces both or well as
模块系统既可以强制执行又可以强制执行
art much as it enforces guarantees
尽力保证
reliable configuration and enforces
可靠的配置并执行
strong encapsulation at both
两者均具有强封装性
compile-time and run-time and there's
编译时和运行时，
some other stuff I can show you if
我可以告诉你一些其他的东西
there's time in the end ok so first
到底有没有时间，所以首先
things first here's here's my my conical
首先，这是我的圆锥形
command line I have a Java here it is
命令行我在这里有一个Java
jk9 yay that's good I always have to
jk9是的，我总是必须这样做
show up J shell because it's just so
显示J Shell，因为它是如此
cool right so J shell if you if you
很酷吧，如果您愿意的话，请J Shell
haven't seen it before I urge you to
在我敦促你去之前还没看过
check it out it's really handy tool we
看看它真的很方便，我们
can do all kinds of you basically you
基本上可以做各种各样的事情
type you type Java code at it and and it
键入您在其中键入Java代码，然后
evaluates it and it gives you a result I
评估它，它给你结果我
won't belabor that here the thing I want
不会感到我想要的东西在这里
to show at this point is is how the
在这一点上显示的是
module system is wired in here there are
模块系统接线在这里
other module systems for Java in some
Java中的其他模块系统
cases there have been some of them have
情况有一些
been around for a long time and they're
已经存在很长时间了
they're good and they're useful for
他们很好，对他们有用
certain kinds of applications but not
某些类型的应用程序但不是
not all but they all live on top of the
并非全部，但它们全都生活在
Java SE platform and that's you know
Java SE平台，就是这样
it's one really one reason why we
这是我们真正的原因之一
couldn't use them to modularize the
无法使用它们来模块化
platform itself the jigsaw module system
平台本身的拼图模块系统
is deeply wired in it's known to the its
深入了解它的
known that the compiler is known to the
知道编译器是已知的
virtual machine so you get a uniform
虚拟机，这样您就可以获得统一
experience at compile-time and run-time
编译时和运行时的经验
so here we are at runtime
所以我们在运行
I can I can make a string save
我可以保存字符串
we know we all know what that's gonna
我们知道我们都知道那会是什么
return right but in nine you can now ask
返回正确的，但在九点，你现在可以问
what is Fu's module and you get back a
傅的模块是什么，你回来
thing that stringify Zinda module drop
Zinda模块掉落的东西
in a base and that itself is an instance
在一个基础上，那本身就是一个实例
of the java.lang model class so there's
java.lang模型类的
a new class java.lang module we can go
我们可以去一个新的类java.lang模块
over here to the Javadoc here's John
在这里到Javadoc，这里是John
easily I mean do you use Java Docs
轻松地说，您是否使用Java Docs
search another cool feature in 9 that is
在9中搜索另一个很酷的功能，那就是
in jigsaw just week we've had Java line
在拼图游戏中，我们有Java行
class for years well modules are as
多年来的课程以及模块
fundamental now as classes always have
就像班上总是有这样的基础
been so I don't why don't that that
所以我不为什么不那样
there's actually somewhat confusingly a
实际上有些令人困惑
package name traveling module 2 but
包名称旅行模块2但
here's the model class and you can find
这是模型类，您可以找到
out all sorts of interesting things
出各种有趣的东西
about a module models has they have
关于模块模型，他们有
exports opens regio all the things that
出口为雷吉奥打开了一切
you can write in a in a module
您可以在模块中编写
descriptor as we shall see
我们将看到的描述符
ok so deeply wired in let's look at
好的，如此深入地探讨
something that is not in the base module
基本模块中没有的内容
you'll know what the base module is
您会知道基本模块是什么
here's the module graph well here's the
这是模块图，这是
standard part of the module graph I'll
模块图的标准部分
pause for the tweets
暂停鸣叫
excellent so there are 26 standard
优秀所以有26标准
modules in Java 9 their relationships
Java 9中的模块及其关系
are indicated here except some aren't
在这里指示，除了一些没有
indicated to get because if I drew in
表示获得，因为如果我参加
all the edges it would be really
所有的边缘，这将是真的
confusing that special module at the
混淆了该特殊模块
bottom Java got base that's the one that
最底层的Java有了基础
contains java.lang object and java.lang
包含java.lang对象和java.lang
string you you pretty much always have
串你几乎总是
to have that around so every module even
到处都有，所以每个模块
modules you write implicitly depend on
您隐式编写的模块取决于
Java code base whether you want to or
Java代码库，无论您想要还是
not and Java dot base of course it
当然不是和Java点库
depends on the other modules because
取决于其他模块，因为
well it's like the very core the very
好吧，就像非常核心
kernel of the system so that's the
系统的内核，所以
module graph
模块图
yep okay where was I
是的，我在哪里
all right let's look at something in a
好吧，让我们来看看
different module let's see here J shells
不同的模块让我们在这里看到J shell
doing completion even on module names
即使模块名称也完成
which is pretty sweet
这很甜
so make myself a sequel timestamp that's
所以让自己成为续集时间戳
an instance of Java sequel timestamp duh
Java续集时间戳duh的实例
and that is in a different module that's
那是在另一个模块中
over in the Java doc sequel module which
在Java doc续集模块中
we look here is a couple steps above
我们看这里是上面几个步骤
Java to base so there's Drive dropping
基于Java的驱动器下降
at C wool two layers above ganden okay
在甘丹上方两层的C羊毛处
so the module system is deeply wired in
因此模块系统已深入连接
it's also we've we've taken great pains
这也是我们付出了极大的努力
as I mentioned yesterday to make sure
正如我昨天提到的，以确保
that it's compatible if you have code
有代码就可以兼容
that uses only standard SC api's and it
仅使用标准SC API的
runs on eight then chances are pretty
在八点上跑，那么机会非常大
good it's gonna run on nine anybody
很好，它将要对九个人进行攻击
remember swingset - this is the swing
记住秋千-这就是秋千
step jar file from from jdk five
来自jdk的步骤jar文件5
released in 2004
2004年发行
it works well I'm pretty nice no problem
它运作良好，我很好，没问题
and click around all of your stuff okay
然后点击所有你的东西好
so compatibility so let's look at look
那么兼容性，让我们来看一下
at our little application here pop into
在我们的小应用程序中弹出
Emacs here you go
Emacs，您去了
all all-in-one all-in-one little screen
所有多合一的小屏幕
package org openjdk hello class main
软件包org openjdk hello类main
it's got a main method that takes an
它的主要方法需要
argument it constructs a string
参数构造一个字符串
it uses a innovative method called left
它使用一种称为left的创新方法
pad to pad Pat it on the left with
垫到垫在左边
spaces to a certain column length in
间隔到一定的列长度
this case 90 and there you go
这个案例90然后你去了
really simple all right let's compile
真的很简单，让我们编译
this in the usual way I want glasses not
这是我通常不想要的眼镜
glazes and packaged it into a jar
釉，装在罐子里
and now I've got hello jar run in the
现在我已经在
usual fashion no to have a completion
惯常的时尚没有完成
here sorry and there we go hello world
在这里对不起，我们去打招呼世界
have a modular world hello sunny world
有一个模块化的世界你好，阳光明媚的世界
there you go okay so that's that's basic
那里你还好，所以这就是基本
so we've got trivial hello world in a
所以我们在一个简单的世界里
simple jar file on the class path just
类路径上的简单jar文件
like we always have let's make it into a
就像我们一直以来，让它成为一个
module how do we do that well what do we
模块我们该如何做得好
need to make it into a module we need a
需要使其成为一个模块，我们需要一个
module declaration we put that in module
模块声明，我们将其放在模块中
info - a module has what does a module
信息-模块具有什么功能
have a module has a name
有一个模块有一个名字
we're using using reverse DNS as
我们正在使用反向DNS作为
recommended this module is only gonna
推荐这个模块只会
use stuff in the base model I could type
在我可以输入的基本模型中使用东西
requires Java got base here but I don't
需要Java在这里有基础，但我没有
need to the compiler will insert that
需要编译器将其插入
for me if I don't
对我来说，如果我不
so most people never do so trivial
所以大多数人从来没有这么琐碎
module it's just named or org openjdk
它只是命名模块或组织openjdk
hello I look at my source tree now I've
你好，我现在看我的源代码树
got the module info there at the top and
在顶部有模块信息
then that class through the same the
然后通过同一类
same way it was there before okay so
之前也一样
let's compile that compile that module
让我们编译那个编译那个模块
info and for now we can just do the do
信息，现在我们可以做
what we did before it's like well it's
我们之前所做的一切都很好
just another Java file we just compile
只是我们编译的另一个Java文件
it okay give it to through Pilar
可以通过皮拉尔给它
sticking in the class of directory now
现在停留在目录类中
we've got a module in for that class we
我们在该课程中有一个模块
can ask Java P what's in there and it
可以问Java P里面有什么
says oh well it here's the module
说哦，好吧，这是模块
declaration that you compiled let's
您编译的声明让我们
let's make our jar file again and now we
让我们再次制作我们的jar文件，现在我们
have modular jar file
有模块化的jar文件
it's got module info class right there I
我那里有模块信息类
can ask the jar command to describe it
可以要求jar命令对其进行描述
and it will go we read the module
它会去，我们阅读模块
descriptor and tell me what's inside was
描述符，告诉我里面是什么
inside there and it doesn't send in a
在里面，它不会发送
simple textual form that's easy for
简单的文本形式，很容易
scripts to parse rather than an source
脚本而不是源脚本
code form so it tells you that this
代码形式，它告诉您
requires Java dot base mandated means
需要Java dot base强制手段
yeah this is mandated by the specs of
是的，这是规范的要求
the compiler inserted it for me and it
编译器为我插入了它
contains a package named orgh orgh open
包含一个名为orgh orgh open的软件包
JDK hello
JDK你好
so we can now run this in modular form
所以我们现在可以以模块化形式运行它
and in modular form we don't use the
而在模块化形式中，我们不使用
class path right we use the good job
正确的上课道路我们会用好工作
excellent you guys have seen this
你们看到的很棒
presentation before
之前的演讲
hello and I tell it my main class there
你好，我告诉我我的主要班级
we go
我们去
modular hello world okay well big deal
模块化的你好世界好吧，好大了
but what's actually going on there that
但是那里到底发生了什么
there's actually quite quite a quite a
实际上有相当一部分
bit of stuff going on here and we'll see
一些东西在这里，我们会看到
more of that now a cool thing about
现在更多的是关于
modular jars is they've got a module in
模块化的罐子里有一个模块
for that class but if you need to you
该课程，但如果您需要
can still run them on the class path so
仍然可以在课程路径上运行它们
just like I did before
就像我以前一样
right then you have that same jar file I
正确的然后你有相同的jar文件
put it on the class path the module
将其放在模块的类路径中
infos ignored this is useful for
信息被忽略，这对于
migration that means that if you if you
迁移意味着如果您
ship a library you can compile all of
提供一个库，您可以编译所有
its classes if you need to force a JDK
它的类，如果您需要强制使用JDK
seven just compiled its module info
七个刚刚编译了其模块信息
class for JDK nine shipped out library
JDK的九个类运出库
users who are running on releases before
在以前版本上运行的用户
nine can just use that jar file on the
九个可以只使用那个jar文件
class path and abusers that are running
类路径和正在运行的滥用者
on nine or later can use it on the class
在九点或更晚的时候可以在课堂上使用它
path or on the module path on the module
路径或模块上的路径
path it'll show up as a module on a
路径将作为模块显示在
class path it'll just be oh a bunch of
上课的路径只是一堆哦
classes on the class path like it always
像往常一样在课程路径上的课程
was all right to simplify things I'm
可以简化我的事情
going to take advantage about another
要利用另一个
feature whoops of the of the jar command
jar命令的功能
and and in fact another another feature
而且实际上是另一个功能
of the module system you can you can
可以的模块系统
when you package up a module you can
打包模块时，您可以
tell the jar tool to insert into the
告诉jar工具插入
module descriptor into module in class
模块描述符到类中的模块
information about what the main class
关于什么主要类的信息
for the module is you can essentially
对于模块，您基本上可以
declare the entry point so I can say
声明入口点，所以我可以说
main class or open JDK hello main
主类或打开JDK hello main
and now when I wrote on the module path
现在当我在模块路径上写时
I don't have to do this I can just name
我不必这样做，我只能说
the module that I want to run as work
我要作为工作运行的模块
openjdk okay hello it's basically now
openjdk好的，你好，基本上是现在
now it's a tiny application module and
现在它是一个很小的应用程序模块，
and it runs there's no need for me to to
它运行，我不需要
say that all right so we've got our
说，好的，所以我们有了
little one module application here since
自此以来很少有一个模块应用程序
this application is so big in order to
这个应用程序太大了
make it easier to maintain let's
让维护更容易
refactor it into two modules so to do
将其重构为两个模块
that we're going to put each module in
我们将把每个模块放在
its own sub tree of the source directory
源目录本身的子树
let's rename source to org open JDK
让我们将源重命名为org open JDK
hello now we've got a restructured
你好，我们已经进行了重组
source tree when Emacs again and let's
源树，当Emacs再次出现时，让我们
do let's do some refactoring so this let
让我们做一些重构，所以让
so let this left Pat Metheny obviously
所以让这显然离开Pat Metheny
we need a separate module for left pad
我们需要一个单独的左垫模块
right I mean if JavaScript has a
对，我的意思是说如果JavaScript有一个
separate module for left path and Java
左侧路径和Java的单独模块
should have a separate module for lap
应该有一个单独的膝盖模块
pad so I'm gonna make a different module
垫，所以我要做一个不同的模块
in this case or open JDK dot txt
在这种情况下，请打开JDK点txt
make a class in there called patter da
在那里上课，叫作pat da
Java copy some of this stuff out okay so
Java将其中一些内容复制出来，这样
it's text it's public class patter I'll
这是文字，这是公共场合的模式
need to make this public okay now we
现在需要让这个公开好了，我们
have pattern it's a module it needs a
有模式，这是一个模块，它需要一个
module descriptor declaration now this
模块描述符声明现在这个
module is exporting something for use by
模块正在导出某些内容以供
the other module by the hello module so
另一个模块是hello模块，所以
I need to say exports its package which
我需要说出口它的包裹
is also named work up a JD tag okay open
也被命名为工作JD标签
org OpenJDK text and then that should be
org OpenJDK文本，然后应该是
it so to finish up let's see I need go
这样结束吧，让我们看看我需要走
fix up the main class here so obviously
很明显地在这里修好主班
don't need this anymore but I do need to
不再需要这个了，但我确实需要
import org openjdk
导入组织openjdk
patter patter and change this right okay
atter沥沥，改变这个权利好吗
that should work you find out
你应该发现的工作
okay to save a little time I've made a
可以节省一些时间，我已经
little command called JJ that does Java
执行Java的称为JJ的小命令
C and jar all in one step so let's see
C和jar一步完成，让我们来看一下
let's compile and package the text
让我们编译和打包文本
module we've got the text module let's
模块，我们有文本模块，让我们
compile and package the Hello module
编译和打包Hello模块
whoops I forgot something and the module
哎呀，我忘了一些东西和模块
system told me what was wrong see I
系统告诉我什么地方出了错
forgot to change the changed the module
忘了更改已更改的模块
info for org open JDK hello and so so
组织的信息打开JDK你好等等
the compiler is saying hey I don't know
编译器说嘿我不知道
where to find this text thing tell me
哪里可以找到这个文字的东西告诉我
where to find it
在哪里找到它
so let's go back to that module info and
因此，让我们回到该模块信息
what I need is what do I need
我需要的是我需要的
where is open dedicated text
打开的专用文字在哪里
okay so that all compiles I've got two
好的，这样所有的编译我都有两个
modules right proper names now we can
模块正确的专有名称，现在我们可以
see if I ask the jar the jar tool to
看看我是否要罐子里的罐子工具
describe hello dot jar I can see it now
描述你好点罐我现在可以看到
requires it up at a base that also
需要它的基础
requires org OpenJDK text and it still
需要组织OpenJDK文本，并且它仍然
contains work of org OpenJDK hello so
包含组织OpenJDK的工作你好所以
let's run this guy
让我们来经营这个家伙
doesn't forgot that didn't I
不会忘记那不是我
there we go so that's now running as a
我们去了，所以现在作为一个
module alright so the module path is is
模块好，所以模块路径是
different than the class path the clad
与班级路径不同的是
the class path has a couple of
课堂上有几个
fundamental flaws and that's that's why
基本缺陷，这就是为什么
it's brittle and error prone if you
如果您易碎且容易出错
think about it the class path is really
想一想，上课的路真的是
it's a way to look up classes its way to
这是一种查找类的方式
look up classes without any regard
无视查找课程
really for what jar files contain them
究竟是什么jar文件包含它们
you know the way the way the compiler in
你知道编译器的方式
the VM searched the class path wrote for
VM搜索了为其编写的类路径
a class is look in the first jar for the
一个类在第一个罐子里寻找
class if that if it's not there look in
如果没有的话，上课
the next one look the next one and so on
下一个看下一个，依此类推
which is why you can get packaged
这就是为什么你可以打包
conflicts and all kinds of other nasty
冲突和其他各种令人讨厌的事情
surprises on the class path the module
在类路径上的惊喜模块
path is a way to find whole modules once
路径是一次查找整个模块的方法
the module system finds one module on on
模块系统在其上找到一个模块
the module path then it will only read
模块路径，那么它只会读取
the packages in that mod in that model
该模型中该模型中的软件包
from that module if some other module is
从该模块，如果其他模块是
resolved and winds up declaring the same
解决，最后宣布相同
package in a way that conflicts then the
打包方式与
module system will report an error and
模块系统将报告错误，并且
stop you know at both at both compile
停止在两个编译时都知道
time and at runtime so let's see some of
时间和运行时，让我们来看一些
those potential failure modes suppose
那些潜在的故障模式
suppose I somehow misplaced the text
假设我以某种方式放错了文字
module
模组
if I try to run things now modular open
如果我现在尝试运行东西，则以模块化方式打开
JD JDK text not found required by org
找不到组织要求的JD JDK文本
open JDK hello the module system tells
打开JDK，您好，模块系统告诉您
you what it was trying to do and what
你它想做什么，做什么
failed if I try to come recompile the
如果我尝试重新编译失败
hello module then again a compile-time
你好模块，然后再次编译
error module not found so there's
错误模块未找到，所以有
there's no there's there's no no
没有没有那里没有
possibility for cheating here and we and
在这里作弊的可能性，我们和
we've tried as much as we can to make
我们尽了最大的努力
both compile-time and run-time work in
编译时和运行时都在
exactly the same way they should they
他们应该完全一样的方式
have a except for some obscure cases
有一些例外情况
they have exactly the same behavior are
他们有完全相同的行为是
great let's let's restore that text guy
太好了，让我们还原那个文本家伙
make sure it runs again yep there we go
确保它再次运行是的，我们去了
all right so another another failure is
好吧，另一个失败是
well we already saw the failure with
好了，我们已经看到了失败
missing requires so I I don't need to
缺少要求，所以II不需要
don't need to show that again another
不需要再次显示
interesting thing that the module system
有趣的是模块系统
guarantees what do you notice about this
保证您对此有何注意
graph mm-hmm it's clean yeah yeah it's
图mm-hmm干净，是的，是的
it's kind of pretty isn't it yours years
这很漂亮，不是你的几年
of hard work went into that
辛苦的工作
there are no cycles very good the module
没有周期很好的模块
system guarantees that there are no
系统保证没有
cycles so I suppose I go to the module
循环，所以我想我去了模块
declaration for the text module and I
文本模块的声明，我
say requires org open JDK
说需要组织开放JDK
hello you know and it might be tempting
你好，你知道，这可能很诱人
to do this if you're modern rising some
如果您是现代人，可以这样做
existing system and you've got to jar
现有系统，你必须要振作起来
files then look kind of like modules but
文件看起来像是模块，但是
each one needs some stuff for the other
每个人都需要一些东西
and you can't figure out how to
而且你不知道如何
disentangle them you know it's a natural
解开它们，你知道这很自然
thing to think oh yeah I'll just make
想的东西哦，是的，我会做
each one require the other but in the
每个人都需要另一个，但在
long run that's probably going to come
从长远来看，这可能会到来
back to bite you so the model system
回到咬你，所以模型系统
just doesn't allow it it's it may see it
只是不允许它是它可能会看到它
may seem harsh but in but it really is a
可能看起来很刺眼，但实际上确实是
better way to live all right so let's
更好的生活方式，让我们
recommit stri to recompile the the text
重新提交stri以重新编译文本
module oh dear
模块哦亲爱的
yeah save it first mark error cyclic
是的，将其保存为第一个标记错误循环
dependence involved evolving or go p--
依赖涉及发展或走向
and JDK hello so you get reliable
和JDK打招呼，让您可靠
configuration not just at runtime but
配置不仅在运行时，而且
also at compile time
也在编译时
alright let's fix that up and then
好吧，让我们修复它，然后
another failure mode is suppose that I
另一个失败模式是假设我
forgot to export this
忘了出口
what'll happen that so I can certainly
这样会发生什么，所以我当然可以
recompile the text module but if I now
重新编译文本模块，但是如果我现在
go and try to run the application again
去尝试再次运行该应用程序
I get an illegal access error classwork
我收到非法的访问错误课堂作业
OpenJDK hello main in module or go to
OpenJDK hello主要在模块中或转到
JDK hello cannot access or go p-- and
JDK hello无法访问或进入-
jdk text patter in module or go p-- and
jdk文本模式在模块中或转到p--
jdk text because text does not or does
jdk text，因为text不存在或不存在
not export the text package to the hello
不将文本包导出到你好
module so it seems kind of remote
模块，所以看起来有点像远程
verbose but this is basically ought Thea
详细，但这基本上应该是Thea
this is like everything the mantra
这就像一切的口头禅
system has to tell you and it will
系统必须告诉您，它将
hopefully be enough information to help
希望有足够的信息来帮助
you debug the problem the problem
您调试问题
there's a quick question
有一个快速的问题
does it give any warnings no this is a
它会发出任何警告吗，这不是一个
heart failure right yeah let's let's
心力衰竭对吧，让我们
take you a after please all right so let
请你一会儿好吧，让
me undo that and now we're back to a
我撤消该操作，现在我们回到
working system all right so a few other
工作系统还可以
words about what's going on here
关于这里发生的事情的话
as far as the mountain as the modular
远至高山
platform is concerned there there are
平台关注那里
these these 26 standard modules the JDK
这些JDK的这26个标准模块
itself actually has quite a few more we
本身实际上还有很多
can see that there's a handy option to
可以看到有一个方便的选择
the Java launcher called Java list
Java启动器称为Java列表
modules whoa
模块哇
there's 75 in in an open JDK build if
如果有一个开放的JDK构建中有75个
you get it if you get an Oracle JDK
如果您有Oracle JDK，就可以得到它
build there are more eventually there
建立那里最终会有更多
will be the same number in each of them
他们每个人都有相同的数字
my after we open source some more stuff
我的开源之后
from the Oracle JDK let me make that a
来自Oracle JDK的让我
little easier to read so on the Left
有点容易阅读，所以在左边
column you can see a bunch of the Java
专栏，您可以看到一堆Java
modules of those are the standard Java
这些模块是标准的Java
SC modules and the right-hand column you
SC模块和您的右侧专栏
can see modules starting with the
可以看到以
letters JDK those are JDK specific some
那些JDK字母是JDK特有的
of the quite a few of them export
其中相当一部分出口
nothing they're just internal
没有什么，他们只是内部的
implementation modules maybe they
实现模块，也许他们
provide an internal service that that's
提供的内部服务
used by other JDK modules in other cases
在其他情况下，由其他JDK模块使用
they contain tools for example you know
它们包含例如您知道的工具
J shell is in its own module some
J Shell在其自己的模块中
internal internal api's are in their own
内部内部api本身
modules and so forth so so that's all
模块等等，仅此而已
that that's a lot of modules I already
那已经是很多模块了
showed you the modular Java doc let's
向您展示了模块化Java文档
just take another quick look at that go
只是再快速看一下
back to the top it's organized into the
回到顶部，它被组织成
front page is organized into three
首页分为三部分
sections you've got this the 26 standard
部分，您已经有了26种标准
SE modules at the top and then the jdk
SE模块位于顶部，然后是jdk
modules in the middle you can say see
您可以说在中间的模块看到
more information about all of these and
有关所有这些的更多信息，以及
then at the bottom we have the JavaFX
然后在底部有JavaFX
modules and then a couple of others that
模块，然后其他几个
are kind of in never-never land
在从未有过的土地上
they're stated with the these are
他们说这些是
oddballs they're standard they're
他们是标准的奇怪球
standard in that they've been
他们的标准是
standardized in the JCP but they're not
在JCP中是标准化的，但不是
part of the Java SC platform
Java SC平台的一部分
specification that's why they're
这就是为什么
classified as other
归类为其他
alright one last thing I'd like to show
好吧，我想展示的最后一件事
you before we go into questions is J
在我们提问之前，您是J
link so I did a quick demo of J link in
链接，所以我做了一个J链接的快速演示
the keynote yesterday J link is how we
昨天的主题演讲J链接是我们
can take a set of application modules
可以采用一组应用程序模块
and merge them together with just the
并与它们合并在一起
subset of the JDK modules that those
那些JDK模块的子集
application module needs modules need in
应用程序模块需求
order to create a compact runtime you
为了创建一个紧凑的运行时
know custom runtime image that you can
知道可以的自定义运行时映像
deploy you can stick in a docker image
部署您可以粘贴在docker映像中
then you had to play to the cloud
那你就得玩云了
through a worker pipeline or whatever
通过工人管道或其他方式
and it'd be much more compact so I have
而且它会更紧凑，所以我有
your here's here's my here's my build of
你的这里是我的这里是我的构建
JDK 9 I've been using I can ask how big
我一直在使用的JDK 9请问有多大
it is and it's 347 megabytes which well
是347兆字节
yeah okay that's kind of big let me make
是的，好吧，让我做
a custom runtime that contains let's see
包含让我们看看的自定义运行时
weld will will start which by making one
焊接将开始通过做一个
that just contains the base module for
只是包含用于
kicks and grows so J Lang Mon droit you
踢和成长，所以J Lang Mon驱使您
the files I need to do this are in the
我需要执行的文件在
j-mods directory here
j-mods目录在这里
so for every module in the JDK there's
因此，对于JDK中的每个模块，
one of these J mod files now these
这些J mod文件之一，现在这些
aren't jar files because they contain
不是jar文件，因为它们包含
things that jar files cannot or should
jar文件无法或应该执行的操作
not contain like native native libraries
不包含本机本机库
you know shared objects dll's whatever
你知道共享对象dll是什么
and so we so we had to had to use a
所以我们不得不不得不使用
different format for the models of the
模型的不同格式
jdk itself J mod is a format that's
jdk本身的J mod是
that's that's documented if you if you
如果你有的话，那就是记录的
need to ship a module with native code
需要附带本机代码的模块
you can use it yourself but for most
您可以自己使用它，但大多数情况下
purposes if you're just dealing with
目的，如果你只是在处理
pure Java than a modular jar file it's
纯Java而不是模块化的jar文件
perfectly fine anyway I've got my j-mods
反正我已经有了我的j-mod
let's let's link a little image here
让我们在这里链接一个小图像
I'll say J link well I gave link takes a
我会说J链接很好，我给的链接花了一个
module path just like the compiler in
模块路径就像编译器在
the runtime I tell it where to put its
运行时，我告诉它放在哪里
results make a directory called JRE you
结果创建一个名为JRE的目录
always have to tell J link which modules
总是必须告诉J链接哪些模块
to add in this case we just want Java
在这种情况下，我们只需要Java
updates and nothing else and J modes not
更新，没有别的，J模式不
J mods marked boy am i spelling today
J Mods标记为“今天我是男孩”
horrible okay there's my tiny JRE and
可怕的是，我的JRE很小，
it's only 43 megabytes
只有43兆字节
now it doesn't get this gets get smaller
现在不会变小
still
仍然
but you know there it is it thinks it's
但你知道那是它认为的
a it's thinks it's a runtime but it
它认为这是一个运行时，但它
doesn't actually have much in it so
实际上没有太多东西，所以
let's make a cuss another custom one
让我们来一个自定义的另一个
that contain a contains our tiny
包含一个很小的
application take this jailing command
应用程序执行此jaail命令
we'll tell it where to find our modules
我们将告诉它在哪里可以找到我们的模块
will output into say HJ r e4 hello JRE
将输出为HJ r e4 hello JRE
and we'll add org OpenJDK hello and this
我们将添加org OpenJDK你好
this won't work excuse me I just need to
请问这是行不通的，我只需要
fix one little thing here
在这里修理一件小东西
there yeah
是的
okay now to work so I run j-link
现在可以工作了，所以我运行j-link
it's a little bit bigger
更大一点
looks wrong Jerry use this one right
杰克（Jerry）看起来不对，请使用这一对
hello world all all bundled up there
你好世界都捆绑在那里
with it with its own little runtime
用它自己的少量运行时
mm-hmm yeah that's that's curious isn't
嗯，嗯，那很好奇不是
it gentlemen front rows pointing out
先生们前排指出
that aah Jerry Jerry is a little bit
那Aah Jerry Jerry有点
smaller I'm not sure why that's a
较小，我不确定为什么会这样
rounding error curious must be that link
舍入错误好奇一定是那个链接
time optimizations guy I not sure but
时间优化家伙，我不确定，但是
it's a good question ought to look into
这应该是一个很好的问题
that we can we can make this smaller
我们可以使它变小
still there are some additional mob
仍然还有一些暴民
options we can use for example strip
我们可以使用的选项例如带
this will make it a lot smaller strip to
这将使其变得更小
get debug information we can compress
获取我们可以压缩的调试信息
class files and we can even ask it to
类文件，我们甚至可以要求它
make a launcher for it for us
为我们做一个发射器
takes a little more time because it's
需要更多的时间，因为
doing more work and now here's our HJRes
做更多的工作，现在这是我们的HJRes
e is only 28 Meg's
e只有28兆
we look in there we have a handy hello
我们看那里，我们很方便
launcher for a tiny application it works
一个很小的应用程序的启动器
so 20 megabytes stick that in a docker
所以20兆字节将其保留在docker中
image with Alpine the Alpine Linux
Alpine的图像Alpine Linux
kernel it'll get up to you know 3035
内核它会起床，你知道3035
drop it drop to play that into cloud and
把它放到云端
you can and you have a hello world in
你可以，你有一个世界你好
the cloud well you probably want to make
您可能想要制造的云
it talk to the web rather than standard
它与网络而非标准对话
outfit okay
穿好衣服
that's the prepared part of this now
这就是现在的准备部分
we've got time for questions for about
我们有时间提问
15 minutes I'm happy to demo demonstrate
15分钟我很高兴演示
other stuff or or just answer questions
其他东西，或者只是回答问题
there's a there's a hand mic here you
这里有一个手咪
want to run around okay great
想跑来跑去好极了
and oh and we'll run around with the
哦，我们将与
MyPlate please wait for the mic because
MyPlate请等待麦克风，因为
the session is being recorded if you
如果您正在录制会话
just shout it out it won't make it to
只是大声喊出来就不会成功
the recording and if I repeat what you
录音，如果我重复你的话
say I'll probably get it wrong okay hi
说我可能会弄错好吧
Peter hi hi muck so this mean well now
Peter hi hi muck，所以这意味着现在
you've got rid of kuba yesterday I
你昨天摆脱了古巴
didn't think we were gonna get rid of it
没想到我们会摆脱它
what about java.util date and and
那java.util日期和
calendar why would we get rid of those
日历为什么我们要摆脱那些
because you've got the new ones the new
因为你有新的
date and time since Java right
自Java正确以来的日期和时间
while we holding onto these or why are
当我们坚持这些还是为什么
those not going to be deprecated Oh
那些不会被淘汰的人哦
rather why couldn't those classes be
而是为什么那些类不能
made into a module in itself okay good
做成一个模块就可以了
questions so double util date if you
问题，如果您有双重使用日期
look at it it's actually almost
看着它实际上几乎
completely deprecated already I believe
我相信已经完全弃用了
but all all of the troublesome aspects
但所有麻烦的方面
in Java util date were deprecated a long
Java util date中的不推荐使用已久
time ago because sorry the classes it's
前段时间因为对不起班
just so bad but there's there's a
太糟糕了，但是有一个
there's a cost-benefit trade-off here
这里有一个成本效益的权衡
right I mean yes we'd like to remove
对，我的意思是，我们要删除
things from from java SE and from the
来自Java SE和
jdk that are no longer you know
不再知道的jdk
compelling as parts of the platform
引人注目的平台
where's parts of the implementation and
实施的哪一部分？
you especially you know think things
你尤其是你知道思考的事情
like you know things like Jax be you
就像你知道贾克斯这样的事情
know jax-ws
知道jax-ws
you the jdk it has never really been the
你的JDK从来没有真正的
proper home for those they're maintained
为他们所维护的人提供适当的家
elsewhere they're part of Java EE if you
如果您在其他地方，它们是Java EE的一部分
need them go get them from you know
需要他们去找你知道的
maven central or wherever wherever you
Maven Central或无论您身在何处
find the EE artifacts so there's really
找到EE工件，所以真的有
you know back it back in the day when
你知道回去的时候
those were added in in Java 6 there was
这些是在Java 6中添加的
an argument that yeah ok we think these
是的，是的，我们认为这些
things are gonna be broadly used put
事情将被广泛使用
them in the jdk because that's we know
他们在jdk中，因为那是我们知道的
that's broadly used and people weren't
被广泛使用，人们却没有
so used to just downloading stuff off
所以以前只是下载东西
the internet but you know we're in a
互联网，但你知道我们在
different world now something like Java
现在像Java一样的不同世界
util day-job you look calendar yes I
util白天工作，你看日历是的，我
totally agree their horrid api's I'm so
完全同意他们的糟糕API，我是如此
happy we got better ones in Java 8 but
很高兴我们在Java 8中有了更好的选择，但是
what would that what would the cost and
那会花多少钱和
benefit be of removing them you know the
好处是删除它们，您知道
the cost would be we would break some
代价是我们会打破一些
existing code because we know because we
现有的代码，因为我们知道，因为我们
often do scans of like many of there are
经常扫描许多
files and they've been central to 0 as
文件，它们一直以0为中心
there are libraries out there that are
那里有图书馆
recent that are using these old crafty
最近正在使用这些老狡猾的人
api's and the answer is yes so yeah ok
api，答案是肯定的，是的，好的
we could we could take those out we'd
我们可以把那些拿出来
break people's code would it save us any
破坏人们的密码会为我们节省任何
maintenance burden
维修负担
maybe a little but in the end yeah
也许一点，但最终
probably not that much and it's probably
可能没有那么多，可能是
not worth breaking people's code just
不值得破坏人们的代码
for that reason so instead Mia where
因此，米娅代替
they are deprecated they're not
他们被淘汰了，他们不是
deprecated for removal but they've been
不建议移除，但它们已经
deprecated for a long time and in in
长时间不推荐使用
most cases you know with with a
您知道的大多数情况下
referencing of go use go use job it out
引用去使用去去工作
time over there it's way better as to
在那里的时间更好
why we can't put Java util date in its
为什么我们不能在其中放置Java util date
own module and then remove that module
自己的模块，然后删除该模块
that the technical reason for that is
技术原因是
modules cannot have conflicting packages
模块不能有冲突的软件包
so Java util has to be in one module
所以Java util必须放在一个模块中
that module is Java dot base we can't
该模块是Java点基础，我们不能
have another you know Java dot broken
有另一个你知道Java点破
dot date module that has Java util date
具有Java使用日期的点日期模块
in it in the same package the module
在同一包装中的模块中
system won't resolve that so in in in in
系统无法解决该问题，所以在in in
earlier prototypes of jigsaw way back in
拼图的早期原型可以追溯到
the day Alan what we'll remember we
那天艾伦，我们会记得我们
actually we struggled with this we
其实我们为此感到挣扎
actually had a prototype that allowed
实际上有一个允许的原型
modules to have conflicting packages and
具有冲突软件包的模块
it it became just a hairball to think
它变成了一个思考的毛线球
about and and reason about and specify
关于和理由，并指定
so we just backed off it's you kind of
所以我们只是放弃了
like forbidding cyclic dependences it's
就像禁止循环依赖一样
a much saner world if you just forbid
如果您只是禁止的话，世界会更健康
conflicting conflicting packages in
冲突的软件包
modules that are related to each other
相互关联的模块
you know in principle if you have a big
你原则上知道如果你有一个大
system with a lot of modules you have
有很多模块的系统
module two over here in module over
模块上方的模块2
there and they never see each other they
在那里，他们再也见不到对方
can have conflicting packages but if one
可以有冲突的软件包，但如果有一个
module you if models are somehow related
模块是否与模型相关
in a graph then then they can't all
在图中，那么他们不能全部
right yeah hi I had a question regarding
是的，嗨，我有一个问题
the access qualifiers for example like
访问限定符，例如
in a class you declare public private
在课堂上，您宣布为公开私人
etc does it make sense to I mean is
等对我来说是有意义的
there any plans for heading into the
有任何计划进入
module so that a particular module can
模块，以便特定模块可以
be either exported or required by
出口或要求
specific modules or so sorry by a model
特定模块，或对不起模型
can let's say you want your model to
可以说您要模型
only be used by some other modules let's
只供其他模块使用
say yes so some sort of X's qualifiers
说是的，所以某种X的限定词
like public private protected etcetera
像公共私人保护等
yes there is a way to do that but but
是的，有一种方法可以做到，但是
not in the way that you just described
不像你刚才描述的那样
there's a feature called qualified
有一个叫做合格的功能
exports so if I go to go into my text
导出，所以如果我去输入文字
module and suppose I want to ensure that
模块，并假设我要确保
only the holo module can use this
只有全息模块可以使用此
package I can say exports org openjdk
包我可以说是出口组织openjdk
text 2 or dot OpenJDK hello
文字2或点OpenJDK你好
and now the hello module can require it
现在hello模块可以要求它
but have said it but if some other
但已经说过，但如果还有其他
module requires that that will cause an
模块要求这将导致
error to be recorded and that this is a
要记录的错误，这是一个
facility we used we used throughout the
我们在整个过程中使用的设施
JDK itself let me show you
JDK本身让我展示给您
[Music]
[音乐]
so here's the module of declaration for
所以这是声明的模块
the base class itself exports a whole
基类本身出口整个
bunch of things what you would expect
一堆东​​西你会期望
Passover services and then it exports a
逾越节服务，然后导出
bunch of things in a qualified fashion
一堆东​​西以合格的方式
to other modules in the JDK so things
到JDK中的其他模块
like JDK internal dot loader to Java
像JDK内部点加载器到Java
instrument and Java dot logging so only
仪器和Java点记录
those modules can read again can you use
这些模块可以再次读取，您可以使用
the api's in in these packages so it's
api在这些软件包中，因此
it's not a facility that many people
这不是很多人的设施
will need to use but when you need it
将需要使用，但是当您需要时
it's it it works quite well now on the
是的，它现在在
on a service that's it might look that
在服务上可能看起来
it's just based on name and you could
它只是基于名称，您可以
think oh well all I need to do to foil
想想，我需要做的所有事情来挫败
this is a is name my module Java dot
这是我的模块Java点名称
instrument right and then I can get to
正确的工具，然后我就可以
the stuff in in this magic package in
这个魔术包里的东西
the base module that's not true because
基本模块不正确，因为
there's an additional mechanism built on
还有一个附加的机制
top of this you can take a collection of
最重要的是，您可以收集
modules and hash them together so your
模块并将它们散列在一起，以便您
winds up recording all the hashes of all
结束记录所有哈希
the modules in in the leaf modules of
的叶模块中的模块
its graph and those hashes will be
它的图和那些哈希将是
checked to ensure the qualified exports
检查以确保出口合格
are being honored in the proper way so
正以适当的方式受到尊重
if you so you could try to masquerade
如果可以的话，你可以尝试假装
your own module name Java that
您自己的模块名称Java
instrument but you still won't be able
乐器，但您仍然无法
to do this so that's how that's one way
为此，这就是一种方式
we ensure the integrity of platform
我们确保平台的完整性
hello I basically have two questions one
你好，我基本上有两个问题
is general and one is more technical so
是一般性的，一种是技术性的，所以
I start with general in what
我从一般开始
circumstances would enterprise
情况会如何
development need to split into modules
开发需要分为模块
in what circumstances in enterprise
企业在什么情况下
development would you need to split
您需要拆分开发
split things into modules well if you
如果您将东西很好地分成模块
know I guess it depends are you happy
知道我猜这取决于你开心吗
are you happy with the class path there
你对那里的上课路满意吗
are tools that does it for me yeah so so
是对我有用的工具
modular right so they're they're kind of
模块化的权利，所以他们有点
multiple multiple answer two answers to
多个多个答案两个答案
this
这个
as things stand because Java has never
就目前情况而言，因为Java从未
had a built in module system you know
有一个你知道的内置模块系统
there are many solutions have grown up
长大了很多解决方案
around the platform to solve parts of
解决平台周围的问题
the modular development programming in a
模块化开发编程
large set of problems right so maven you
一大堆问题对吧，让您了解一下
can think of as sort of a model system
可以认为是一种模型系统
at build time but there are limits to
在构建时有限制
what maven can enforce because after all
Maven可以强制执行什么，因为毕竟
pre nine it's just dealing with jar
九点之前它只是在处理罐子
files on a class path which are
类路径上的文件是
completely leaky and not really I mean
完全泄漏，不是我真正的意思
jar files jar files on the class path
jar文件jar文件放在类路径中
give leaky abstractions a bad name right
给泄漏的抽象起一个不好的名字
there they're just file systems on
那里只是文件系统
sticks so you know maybe it helps it
坚持，所以你知道也许有帮助
helps a bit with that if you're building
如果您正在构建，则对此有所帮助
an EEE application the traditional style
EEE应用程序的传统风格
you'll have deployment descriptors and
您将拥有部署描述符，并且
all of this other other groups that put
所有其他这些其他团体
that assembles EE applications and that
组装EE应用程序，
works what we're trying to do is
我们正在努力做的是
establish a foundation for for a better
为更好奠定基础
future right we're not not replacing all
未来的权利，我们不会取代所有
that stuff all that other stuff will
所有其他东西都会
continue to work fine probably forever
继续工作可能永远
but certainly if you're developing new
但是可以肯定的是，如果您正在开发新的
code I think it's worth thinking about
我认为值得考虑的代码
starting with modules from the get-go so
从一开始就使用模块
the so that your code can benefit from
以便您的代码可以从中受益
reliable configuration and strong
配置可靠，坚固
encapsulation in all phases of
封装的所有阶段
development you can use the linker if
开发您可以使用链接器，如果
you don't if you don't have modules you
如果没有模块，就没有
can't use j-link that's you know that
不能使用j-link就是这样
there's enough there's another benefit
够了，还有另一个好处
to it but you know as I said in the
它，但你知道，正如我在
keynote yesterday Y wide adoption of the
昨天主题演讲Y广泛采用了
module system is
模块系统是
is going to take time and it's really
需要时间，这真的
hard to take an existing system and
很难采用现有系统
modularize it and if you have such a
模块化它，如果您有这样的
system it might not be worth it right if
系统可能不值得，如果
it works fine as it is and you don't
它工作正常，但您却没有
expect to do a lot of new development
期望做很多新的发展
then you know stick with your current
那么你知道坚持你的当前
build system and and whatever other
构建系统及其他
tools that you're using but if you're
您正在使用的工具，但如果您正在
good if you're going to start start a
很好，如果你要开始
greenfield project then then consider
新建项目，然后考虑
using modules there are benefits to it
使用模块有好处
so you got a technical question as well
所以你也有一个技术问题
yes I saw in one of the presentations
是的，我在一次演讲中看到了
there are static requires transitive
有静态需要传递
cars
汽车
yes could you give some description to
是的，你能给一些描述吗
use right so so there there are there
使用权，所以那里有
are more elements to to module
还有更多要模块的元素
declarations than I've been able to show
比我能证明的声明
here I'm not sure I'm not sure if Alex
在这里我不确定我不确定亚历克斯
Alex may have covered these in
亚历克斯可能已经涵盖了这些
yesterday's presentation I didn't see
昨天的演讲我没看
his I didn't see his final really didn't
他我没看到他的决赛真的没有
touch okay core static yeah so so
触摸好核心静态是这样
they're there they're there are
他们在那里他们在那里
additional things that probably the most
最可能的其他事情
important one is is requires transitive
重要的是需要传递
let me just explain that one quickly in
让我快速解释一下
the little time remaining
剩下的时间很少
right so Rico so requires when you're
对，所以Rico要求您在
right
对
hello requires text that makes the
你好需要使
exported packages of the text module
文本模块的导出包
accessible to code in the hello module
可访问hello模块中的代码
but suppose suppose Hello itself were
但是假设你好自己是
you it was going to explain you exported
你这将解释你出口
something suppose it exports Oracle JDK
假设它可以导出Oracle JDK
hello and suppose there was a class in
你好，假设有一堂课
Oregon with JDK hello those was say a
俄勒冈州的JDK，你好，有人说
subclass of some class in Oregon and JDK
俄勒冈和JDK中某个类的子类
text all right you can do that but now
可以发短信，但是现在可以
if some model that requires org open JDK
如果某些模型需要组织开放JDK
hello it will have to require Oracle
你好，它将需要Oracle
viniq a text to in order to use that
viniq文本以使用该文本
class you just made so what you can do
你刚做的课，所以你可以做什么
is say requires transitive and what this
是说需要传递和这是什么
does is introduce a one step additional
这样做是引入了一个额外的步骤
transitive relationship so that what
传递关系
this means is any module that requires
这意味着需要任何模块
org openjdk hello will implicitly also
org openjdk hello也会隐式地
require org openjdk text so if you're
需要组织openjdk文本，所以如果你是
defining an API for other modules to use
定义供其他模块使用的API
and that API contains classes or
该API包含类或
interfaces from a module that your
来自您的模块的接口
module uses then requires transitive is
模块使用则要求传递是
you're providing a benefit to the users
您正在为用户带来利益
of your module by making you know
让你知道你的模块
basically reducing the amount of work
基本上减少了工作量
they have to do it is a commitment
他们必须这样做是一种承诺
though because once you requires
尽管因为一旦您需要
transitive you're basically taking on
你基本上是在传递
the responsibility to be providing those
提供这些的责任
other packages to any model that uses
其他包到使用任何模型的
your modules so it's so just as with
您的模块，就像
exports you want to think carefully
您想仔细考虑的出口
about well if I'm exporting this now do
很好，如果我现在要导出此文件
I still want to be exporting it two
我仍然想将其导出两个
years from now or is it gonna come back
几年后还是会回来
to bite me because it's really an
咬我，因为这真的是
internal API
内部API
wait wait wait for the microphone please
请稍等
recorded that's a good segment towards
记录下来是一个很好的细分
like going forward how do you envisage
喜欢前进，你如何设想
this to work going forward with terms of
这将继续与
versioning internally in the JDK and
在JDK内部进行版本控制
then also externally like once these
然后在外部就像这些
modules change and like whatever is in
模块发生变化，就像里面的东西一样
say open JDK text is different now right
说打开的JDK文本现在不一样了
so so some modules in the jigsaw mob
所以拼图中的一些模块
system do not have have versions right
系统没有正确的版本
there are no version constraints you can
没有版本限制
add version information to a module as a
将版本信息添加为模块
matter of documentation when I did this
我这样做时的文档问题
you may it may have noticed there
你可能已经注意到了
they're all these at 9s that means the
这些都是9点，这意味着
version number inserted by the build
内部版本插入的版本号
system for diagnostic purposes is nine
用于诊断目的的系统是九
but the module system doesn't do
但是模块系统不起作用
anything more than convey this
除了传达这一点之外
information so that you can diagnose and
信息，以便您可以诊断和
debug a system that's not working
调试无法正常工作的系统
properly the important thing in this
正确的重要
design is but modules are highly are a
设计是很重要的，但是模块是
different concept than the artifacts
与人工制品不同的概念
that define them artifacts have version
定义工件的版本
numbers and and that's great and that's
数字，那很棒，那是
good and tools like maven help deal with
好东西，像maven这样的工具可以帮助处理
conflicts amongst them but the module
他们之间的冲突，但模块
system is only dealing with modules in
系统仅处理模块中的
terms of their names and if it needs to
他们的名字和是否需要
ensure integrity we have the hashing
确保完整性，我们有哈希
mechanism for that so you know and and
这样的机制，所以你知道和
and going forward I expect modules in
并展望未来，我期望模块
the JDK every time there's data key
每次有数据密钥时，JDK
release we'll have a different version
发布，我们将有一个不同的版本
number but it will not be the case that
数字，但事实并非如此
what one might think that well if we
如果我们能想到的那么好
don't change anything in in the JDK J
不要在JDK J中更改任何内容
shell module in JDK 10 or 18.3 then
然后使用JDK 10或18.3中的shell模块
it'll still be JDK or JDK dot J link at
它仍然是JDK或JDK点J链接，网址为
9 in that release now alone though
虽然现在只有9个版本
they'll all have the same version number
他们都有相同的版本号
they'll be hashed together to protect
他们将被散列在一起以保护
the integrity of the platform that
平台的完整性
that's that's it we're out of time I'm
那就是我们没时间了
afraid thank you very much
害怕非常感谢你
[Applause]
[掌声]